Too much is never enough.
Havoc is a crime, drama film directed by Barbara Kopple.
A wealthy Los Angeles teen and her superficial friends wants to break out of
suburbia and experience Southern California's "gangsta" lifestyle.
But problems arise when the preppies get in over their heads
and provoke the wrath of a violent Latino gang.
Suddenly, their role-playing seems a little too real.
Allison Lang, played by Anne Hathaway.
Emily, played by Bijou Phillips.
Amanda, played by Shiri Appleby.
Stuart Lang, played by Michael Biehn.
Sam, played by Joseph Gordon-Levitt.
Eric, played by Matt O'Leary.
Havoc is a 2005 crime drama film directed by Barbara Kopple from a screenplay
by Stephen Gaghan, who wrote the story with Jessica Kaplan.
The film stars Anne Hathaway, Bijou Phillips, and Mike Vogel.
It follows the lives of wealthy Los Angeles teenagers whose exposure to hip hop culture inspires them to imitate the gangster lifestyle and engage in slum
tourism; they run into trouble when they encounter a gang of drug dealers, discovering they are not as street-wise as they had thought.
Shiri Appleby, Freddy Rodriguez, Joseph Gordon-Levitt, Channing Tatum,
Michael Biehn, and Laura San Giacomo appear in supporting roles.
It is an international co-production between the United States and Germany.
Havoc made its world premiere at the Filmfest München on June 26,
2005, and was shown at several film festivals.
It was released directly on DVD in the United States on November 29, 2005.
The film explores themes of high school, hip-hop,
street gang, upper class, fight.
The tone is dark and emotional.